ABDULLAHI TOHEEB

Software Developer

Lagos, Nigeria (+234) 704-561-9906 biodunbio14@gmail.com https://toheebb.netlify.app https://github.com/majorshuga

SKILLS

React Node
ExpressJs MongoDB
Redux-Toolkit Javascript
Git Laravel
python mySql

Html Cascading Style Sheet (CSS)

NestJs C programming

BootstrapREST APIMongoDB

devops

Unix shell scripting

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A committed and proactive software developer who specializes in the use of programming techniques to develop creative and innovative applications tailored towards specific requirements. Able to work well on own initiative while demonstrating the organizational and prioritization required to achieve tight deadlines. A motivational and inspirational leader who enjoys being part of a successful and productive team.

OBJECTIVE

development. Currently looking for an internship role, one which will make use of my existing skills and experience while enabling further personal and professional

EXPERIENCE

UNITED STATES OF AFRICA, Volunteering - (Remote) Front end developer

April 2023 - To Present

Responsibilities

- Meeting with the development team to discuss user interface ideas and applications.
- Reviewing application requirements and interface designs.
- Identifying web-based user interactions.
- Developing and implementing highly responsive user interface components using

react concepts.

- Writing application interface codes using JavaScript following react.js workflows.
- Troubleshooting interface software and debugging application codes.
- Developing and implementing front-end architecture to support user interface concepts.
- Monitoring and improving front-end performance.
- Documenting application changes and developing updates.

EVERYTHING FROZEN, Full Time - Software engineer

Feb 2020 - March 2022

Responsibilities

- Analyzing user requirements and defining system functionality.
- Designing, developing and updating company website
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams including product managers, designers and quality assurance engineers.
- Debugging and fixing software defects.
- Maintaining and improving the performance of existing software.
- Staying up to date with emerging technologies and industry trends.

Hielite Technologies, Hybrid - Instructor html/css/javascript

Sept 2019 - Oct 2020

Responsibilities

- Assisted in reviewing and identifying existing learning resources for curation for the course specific needs.
- Prepared the students for success by providing coaching in all aspects of their journey towards becoming critical thinkers and problem solvers.
- Monitored student engagement, provides online student support including feedback on their performance.
- Conduct code reviews, grading class exercises, projects and publish assessment feedback.
- Created relevant learning content, documents and practice activities.

Kudi Crypto, Remote Nigeria - Front end developer

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

Responsibilities

- Developed and maintained the front-end of web applications using react.
- Build and integrate back-end services using Node.js.
- Designed and implemented database structures and optimizing database performance.
- Debugging and fixing issues across the entire stack.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams including designers, product managers, and quality assurance engineers.
- Writing and maintaining technical documentation.

EDUCATION

University of Ilorin, Kwara, Nigeria - B.sc Mathematics

Dec 2015 - Sep 2019